#81 Peter's Field Main Road, Chaguanas, Trinidad, West Indies. 705-8671/271-0672 reesh\_1@hotmail.com

Dear Sir/Madam,

I wish to be considered for employment with your firm in a position that is commensurate with my experience and qualifications as indicated in the attached résumé.

I am a self-motivated individual, committed to meeting and surpassing expectations. I thrive on new challenges and my strong desire to deliver, along with my eagerness to learn and self-develop, will prove to be an asset to your organization. I am confident that my experience along with my formal education will enable me to contribute significantly to the organization's overall objectives.

Thank you for your consideration in reviewing my application and I look forward to a personal interview at your convenience.

Sincerely,

Vareesha Latchman

Vareesha Latchman

# Résumé for Vareesha Latchman

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Vareesha Latchman

Address: #81 Peter's Field Main Rd, Chaguanas.

Phone: 705-8671 or 271-0672

Email: reesh\_1@hotmail.com

### **PROFILE**

I am a team player, well organized, and flexible in interpersonal relations with a commitment to quality, thoroughness and excellence. I am a self-starter, and quick learner, with a versatile skill set and **experience in customer service, sales, general accounting, payroll, inventory management, and information technology support services and training**. I am committed to adopting and implementing innovative practices which improve efficiency and productivity in the organization at which I am employed.

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To apply my knowledge, skills, competencies and experience towards improving the operating efficiencies of an organization in meeting its strategic goals.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Aug 2017 – Present** Guardian Shared Services Limited

#1 Guardian Drive, Westmoorings.

<u>Vendor Performance Analyst</u> – This is a contract position within the IT Service Desk Department which provides me with the opportunity to assist the company with its management of day to day vendor operations and performance against service level agreements (SLAs) and key performance indicators (KPIs). My responsibilities involves the following:

#### • Monitor performance and compliance of Enterprise Vendors

- o Working with vendors to ensure SLAs are met
- Establishing and maintaining measures to monitor and collect service level data.
- Evaluating performance and providing regular and formal reporting of service agreement performance, including deviations from the agreed-on values.

- o Distributing reports to stakeholders as required
- Reviewing trend analysis reports identifying any significant issues, initiating actions where necessary, and ensuring that all outstanding issues are followed up.
- Providing the appropriate management information to aid performance management.
- o Ensuring internal stakeholders meet SLA obligations for vendors
- o In multivendor environments, overseeing or managing service integration across multiple internal and external providers

# Vendor Performance Improvement of Enterprise Vendors

- Ensuring that vendors perform root-cause analysis as needed and agree on action plans and remediation for any performance issues or negative trends.
- Escalating as required if performances are below agreed standards and tracking penalties that occur.
- o Ensuring vendors and internal stakeholders meet all other contractual obligations including Compliance and Audit requirements
- Providing data to persons for both new and renewing of service agreements and contracts
- Providing input to the evaluation and selection of vendors and input to new and renewal contract negotiations and SLA development
- o Building rapport with the vendors

## Nov 2016 – Feb 2017 Vibrant Technologies Ltd.

#65 Chin Chin Rd, Cunupia.

<u>WTP Concierge</u>— This was a temporary position which provided me with the opportunity to assist **BP Trinidad and Tobago** with their roll-out and delivery of Windows10 laptops to each of their employees. My responsibilities involved the following:

- Preparation of Pre-deployment checklists for each employee listed on a daily schedule provided
- Ensuring scheduled targets were met by corresponding with employees via telephone and email to confirm and remind them of their Migration appointments.
- Meeting and greeting employees upon entering the Migration room, to have them verify their Pre-deployment checklist before handing them over to the Migration team
- Follow up with employees to provide updates of their deployment status and inform them of its completion.
- Assist the Migration team with the Windows 10 installation and preparation of laptops for the migration.
- Provide updates to the respective team leads throughout the day to keep them informed on work progress

- Prepare and complete relevant project status reports (*Build and Deploy and Deployment Tracker*) on a daily basis for submission to the Project Manager.
- Verify deployment with the employees to ensure the migration was completed to their satisfaction.

# Nov 2014 – Nov 2016 Ministry of Public Utilities formerly the Ministry of Environment and Water Resources,

Level 7, Tower C International Waterfront Center.

<u>Undergraduate Trainee</u> – This was a contractual position, which provided me with the opportunity to assist the I.T. department of the Ministry in its delivery of End User support and solutions in enabling effective service provision by the Ministry. Some of the activities in which I have been involved included:

- Planning, preparing and conducting End User training for hardware (such as phones) and software such as Microsoft Office 365 and Lync.
- Preparation of Request for Quotations as part of the procurement process for the acquisition of IT equipment and services.
- Assisting in the maintenance and collation of all IT related inventory within the Ministry.
- Configuration and distribution of cell phones and laptops along with the relevant contracts to all senior staff within the Ministry.
- Call center management team member for both the fire and hunting hotlines, generating the relevant call management reports for use and address within the Ministry.
- Collation and distribution of bi-weekly reports on phone usage within the Ministry. This included both forestry and drainage divisions along with head office.
- Relocation of IT hardware on the Ministry's change of location.
- Team lead in the removal and relocation of the Ministry's multimedia system.
- Address requests for technical assistance in person of via the phone, providing excellent customer service to all IT users.
- Diagnose and resolve technical hardware and software issues and advise user on appropriate action.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware operating systems and applications.
- Support the roll out of new applications
- Setting up new user's accounts and profiles.

# Jul 2011 – Aug 2014 Trinidad and Tobago Security Services LTD

#117 John & Henry St, Montrose, Chaguanas.

**Payroll Clerk** - with responsibilities for the following:

- Payroll processing which includes
  - o Data entry and verification
  - o Assisting in the final process of compiling all data to pay staff

- o Interacting with supervisors and managers to provide them with rosters to obtain employee payroll details to facilitate accurate processing
- Accounts processing utilizing the database application: Payroll Plus
- Addressing all inquiries regarding the company's payroll
- Filing out all the data at the end of the month
- Preparation of sales invoices and daily sales report

### Nov 2009 – Feb 2010 Customs and Excise Plipdeco CES Unit,

Point Lisas Industrial Estate.

<u>Clerical Assistant</u> – this was a temporary position interfacing between Customs Officers and Customs Clerks in the collection and recording of shipping documents to facilitate the release of goods.

## June 2005 - July 2009 Accellular Company Trinidad Ltd

Building #3 Maka Complex, Williams St, Champs Fleurs

I was employed in the Operations Department of Accellular Company Ltd where I started as a *Customer Service Representative/ Quality Control Assistant* and moved on to a *Purchasing and Traffic Officer*. At Accellular I was introduced to Microsoft Dynamics SL which was used for inventory and billing management. My responsibilities over the period are detailed below

### June 2008- July 2009: Purchasing and Traffic Officer

- Oversee and manage the entire work process of goods from order to distribution.
- Assign locations for stock based on stock movement.
- Process purchase orders.
- Liaise with Vendor, Purchasing, Sales and Finance management on order status and updates
- Generate inventory aging report and use it to monitor inventory and make recommendations to the Sales team to facilitate disbursement based on First in First out method (FIFO).
- Perform stock count to validate inventory based on purchases and sales
- Prepare daily, weekly and monthly sales and receipts reports.
- Conduct Performance Appraisals for my staff

# November 2005 – May 2008: Customer Service Representative/ Quality Control Assistant

- Process sales orders and initiate the work process, corresponding with the Finance department to ensure all orders are credit released for processing.
- Advise customers on pending deliveries and other queries

- Assist the Quality Control Officer with sampling of products received to verify quality standard.
- Generate daily and monthly sales reports for recording.
- File all respective documents, for example order confirmations, picking and packing slips, invoice and delivery notes.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

2005-2010: B.Sc. Computing and Information Systems

School of Business and Computer Science

2002-2005: GCE Advanced Level Certificate

Presentation College, Chaguanas

Mathematics Geography Biology

General Paper

1997-2002: CXC Ordinary Level Certificate

Holy Faith Convent, Couva

English A
English B
Mathematics
Geography
Biology

## **ADDITIONAL TRAINING**

2003: A+ In Computer Literacy

Upper Level Educational Institute

Knowledgeable in Microsoft Word, Excel and Access

2017: Financial Management

PPM& Projects

Infrastructure & Operations
Service Planning & Architecture
Data & Business Intelligence

People & Resources

InfoTech Academy & Research Group